我不知道 我是说 有点伤感
I don't know, man. I mean, I'm kind of sad.
那些高楼就是我的家
Them Towers be home to me.
你现在是要为公房痛哭流涕了?
You gonna cry over a housing project now?
要我说他们早该把那些破烂炸了
Man, they should have blew the motherfuckers up a long time ago you ask me.
它也没那么糟啦
Man, it ain't all been bad.
我是说 我见过高楼区发生的一些事...
I mean, I done seen some shit happen up in them Towers...
至今还能让我会心一笑
that still make me smile, yo.
再过一会儿 我身后这栋不幸代表着...
A few moments from now, the Franklin Terrace Towers behind me...
这城市最根深蒂固的顽疾的Franklin大楼...
which, sadly, came to represent some of this city's most entrenched problems...
就要倒了
will be gone.
你们说的不过是堆钢筋混凝土 伙计 钢筋混他妈的凝土
Y'all talking about steel and concrete, man. steel and fucking concrete.
伙计 我说的是人 还有回忆之类的
Man, I'm talking about people, memories and shit.
那不一样
That ain't the same.
听着 他们要拆旧房 建新房
Look, they gonna tear this building down. They gonna build some new shit.
但人呢 他们压根不关心人
But people? They don't give a fuck about people.
你们即将见证...
You are very soon going to see...
廉价适中的房屋拔地而起
low and moderately priced houses...built in their place.
好
Yeah!
我表兄以前住221 我老在那混
My cousin used to live in 221. I used to be up in there all the time.
还用你说 我在那泡到了人生第一个妞
Man, who you be telling? I caught my first pussy up in there.
那个叫Chantay的女孩
The girl, Chantay.
伙计 你怎么不早说
Man, why didn't you say something before?
说不定他们就不拆楼了
They probably wouldn't be tearing this tower down now.
他们就可以在楼前挂个大标语
They could put a big-ass sign in the front that says,
上面写"在这里Malik Carr首次弄湿他老二"
"Here's where Malik Carr first got his dick wet."
你懂我意思吧
You know what I'm saying, too?
我们可以拍照 还能让游客拍照
We could be taking pictures. Tourists be taking pictures and shit.
还有这么大小的 你的仿真老二纪念品
Souvenirs of your dick about this size.
一点都不搞笑 他只是嫉妒罢了
He ain't funny, yo. He just jealous.
什么 嫉妒那个? 你疯了吗 那个Chantay?
What? Jealous of that? You crazy? Chantay?
伙计 一听到她名字 我鸡巴就犯疼
Man, the mention of that bitch make my dick burn.
嘿 她可不脏 傻帽
Yo, ain't no bad pussy, fool.
是啊 他们在诊所里 一直叫你坐下时 也是这么说的
Yeah, that's what they keep telling your ass down at the clinic, man.
你就嘴硬吧
Keep that shit up.
你见过这混球进性病诊所的样子吗
You ever see this motherfucker when he walking down to the clinic burnt?
Poot就像这样 像个屁股长在前面的牛仔
Poot be like this. He looks like a backwards-ass cowboy and shit.
不是那样 伙计 而是这样走路
Instead of like this, homie, here, walking like this.
老二就像个炸鸡翅
Dick looking like a fried chicken wing.
我们犯过错
Now, mistakes have been made.
但我们会从它们中吸取教训
And we will learn from those mistakes.
改革不仅仅是我和我行政团队的口号
Reform is not just a watchword with my administration.
- 不 那是宗旨 - 好
- No, it's a philosophy. - Yeah!
靠 伙计 不管中多少次招...
Shit, man, no matter how many times you get burnt, man...
你还是会重蹈覆辙
you just keep on doing the same.
黑鬼不会吸取教训
Nigga do not learn.
现在 你们怎么说
Now, what do you say, huh?
你们准备好迎接一个新的Baltimore了吗
Are you ready for a new Baltimore?
它就要灰飞烟灭了
Shit gonna be off the hook, yo.
伙计 我这辈子都在高楼区度过
Man, my whole life been around them Towers, you know?
我是说 我觉得...
I mean, I feel...
靠 我有种无家可归的感觉
Shit, I feel like I don't got no home no more.
房屋署不是让你妈搬到Poplar Grove去了吗?
Housing just moved your mama up to Poplar Grove, didn't it?
你不是无家可归 黑鬼 你有家
You ain't homeless, nigga, you got a home.
靠 你顶多是快失业了
Shit, you just damn near out of work is all.
- 什么意思 - 我是说 你看 整个城市...
- What you mean? - I mean, look. All over the city...
甚至是乡下郡里 到处都是人 可卡因或兴奋剂 全年无休
even out in the county, you had people, coke or dope, 24/7.
现在他们要上哪去?
Where was it they go?
你看 你住在公房区 算个鸟 但在这卖货呢
Man, look, you live in the projects. You ain't shit. But you sling product here?
你就是做主的大爷 伙计
You got the game by the ass, man.
靠 现在这些城里来的衣冠禽兽...
Shit, now these downtown suit-wearing-ass bitches...
把最好的地盘从你们手中抢了过去
done snatched up the best territory in the city from y'all.
你想哭丧 就哭哭这个吧
You wanna cry over some shit, cry over that.
好了 各位 跟我一起倒数
All right, everyone. Count with me.
10 9...
Ten, nine...
8 7...
eight, seven...
6 5...
six, five...
4 3 2 1
four, three, two, one!
狗日的
Oh, shit.
火线重案组 第三季 第一集 周而复始
The Wire S03E01 Time After Time
《Way Down in the Hole》 第三季演唱：纳什维尔兄弟乐队（The Neville Brothers）
* When you walk through the garden *
* You gotta watch your back *
* Well I beg your pardon *
* Walk the straight and narrow track *
* If you walk with Jesus *
* He's gonna save your soul *
* You gotta keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* He's got the fire and the fury *
* At his command *
* Well you don't have to worry *
* If you hold on to Jesus hand *
* We'll all be safe from Satan *
* When the thunder rolls *
* Just gotta help me keep the devil *
* Way down in the hole *
* You gotta help me keep the devil *
"不管中多少次招 你还是会重蹈覆辙"  ---Bodie
操 我踩到狗屎了
Fuck! I just stepped in dog shit.
想得美
You hope.
操
Fuck.
是Cheese吗 能看见他吗?
It's Cheese? Can you see him?
- 他在哪 - 你说谁
- Yo, where he at? - Who you mean?
Cheese 伙计 我在找Cheese
Cheese, man. I'm looking for Cheese, man.
黑鬼 你怎么能把名字说出来
Nigga, you ain't supposed to be dropping names and shit.
有没有常识?
Ain't you got no sense?
我又没说什么不该说的 伙计
I ain't said shit about shit, man.
我只是想找他 伙计
I'm just looking to get together with the man, man.
不为什么事
To see him about nothing at all.
那他在他该在的地方 傻帽
So he be where he be, fool.
我们上次去过的地儿?
Is he at the place that we was at?
因为我要 你知道 备马...
'Cause I'm looking to, you know, saddle up...
然后在那混球身上再下一注
and then put another bat on this motherfucker.
他要么今天跟我交易 要么我就找别人了 伙计
He need to deal with me today or I'm gonna take it to someone who can handle it, man.
- 没什么大不了的 我们会让他明白 - 好吧
- It's nothing. We let him know. - All right.
"备马 然后在那混球身上再下一注"?
"Saddle up and put another bat on the motherfucker"?
备马和再下一注
Settle up and put another bet.
最后那部分是什么来着
But what was that last part?
那人说 "他要么今天跟我交易...
Man said, "He need to deal with me today...
"要么我就找别人了"
"or I'm gonna take it to someone who can handle it."
美女 你耳力真好
Girl, you do have an ear.
- 他想见面 - 好的
- He's looking to get with him. - All right.
一切照旧?
Same thing as before?
- 我就是这么对他说的 - 好的
- Same thing I told him. - All right.
你看见什么了
What are you seeing?
电话打到Cheese的二把手那
Call comes in to Cheese's number two.
然后到他边上耳语了几句 接着所有人都走了
He whispers in the man's ear and off they go.
好吧 这边电话也没戏
Yeah. Nothing to the call here.
早料到了
I figured that.
这些家伙懂事了
These guys come correct.
电话点到即止
The phones only go so far.
其他的都是面谈
Above that, it's all done as a face-to-face meet.
都三个月了
Three months
我们还没听到过他的声音
and we've yet to hear his voice.
Herc抄小巷 切断Calhoun街
And Herc takes the alley to cut that off from Calhoun.
那我和Truck要开车在Stricker街逆行?
So, me and Truck go up the wrong way on Stricker Street?
你有警徽 忘了吗
You got a badge, remember?
而我们在另一个街区也如法炮制 这样他们也逃不进那儿了
And we're doing the same one block over so they can't come to ground that block neither.
重点是 我们冲过去抓那些混蛋时...
Now, the thing is, when we jump out on these little cocksuckers...
通常会有指定的"逃犯"
there'll be a designated runner.
他会跳出来 引我们去追
Who's gonna sky up, just so we get to chase his ass.
但管他呢
But fuck him.
我们放他走 把留在原地的混球全部生擒
We let him go and jack every other motherfucker who stays.
开工吧
Let's mount up.
Carv
Carv.
怎么了
What's up?
"他是个复杂的人"
He's a complicated man.
背景音乐的歌词 著名黑人警探电影主题曲
"唯一懂他的只有他马子"
And the only one that understands him is his woman.
找个医生看看
Seek therapy.
缉毒警 缉毒警!
Narcos. Narcos!
把手举起来 举起来
Let's see your hands! See your hands!
举起手来 面墙站着
See your hands, up against the wall!
- 举起手来 举起手来 - 举起手来 面对墙壁
- Put your hands up. Put your hands up. - Put your hands up against the wall.
- 别推我 - 举手 保持姿势
- You ain't gotta push me. - Hands upstairs. Keep your hands up.
- 身上有东西吗 - 来了
- Anything on you? - Here he goes.
回见 小子 悠着点跑
Later, son. Step light.
嘿 那是包毒品?
Yo, was that the stash?
靠
Fuck!
走 走 在Stricker街拦下他
Let's go, let's go! Cut him off on Stricker.
我到Calhoun街了 你们在哪
I've got Calhoun. Where you at?
跟丢了 Stricker街后巷 800街区
Lost him. Rear of Stricker, 800 block.
Riggs街没人
Clear on Riggs.
他刚从巷子穿过Stricker街 往Gilmor街去了
He just went across Stricker in an alley headed for Gilmor.
哪头?在哪?!
Which end? Which end?!
靠
Fuck.
兔子跑进Gilmor和Riggs街的巷子
We got rabbit in the alleys near Gilmor and Riggs.
- 派点支援吧 - 收到
- How about some backup? - Roger that.
Dozerman 你的位置? 嘿 Doze 你在哪 伙计?
Dozerman, what's your 20? Hey, Doze, where you at, man?
- 他穿过Stricker街了吗 - 绝对的
- Did he cross Stricker? - Definitely.
大家都往那儿去..
Everybody...
谁为哥们两肋插刀? (也是改编自同一首歌词)
Who is the man that would risk his neck for his brother man?
他跑到这街区里了 伙计
He went to ground in this block, man.
嘿 听着 你这小瘪三
Hey, listen to me, you little fucking piece of shit!
我告诉你且只告诉你一件事...
I'm gonna tell you one thing, and one thing only...
关于我们这群 你正在捉弄的西区警察
about the Western boys you are playing with!
我们从不失败
We do not lose!
也从不忘记
And we do not forget!
更从不放弃
And we do not give up!
从不
Ever!
所以我只说一次
So I'm only gonna say this one time.
如果你现在自己站出来戴上手铐...
If you march your ass out here right now and put the bracelets on...
我们就不把你揍得屁滚尿流
we will not kick the living shit out of you!
但如果你害我们跑到杂草里找你...
But if you make us go into them weeds for you...
或者逼我们明晚回到这...
or if you make us come back down here tomorrow night...
在一个街角抓到你 我它妈的对天发誓...
catch you on a corner, I swear to fucking Christ...
我们会把你揍到惊天地 泣鬼神!
we will beat you longer and harder than you beat your own dick!
你逃不掉的 傻鸟 我们才是赢家
'Cause you do not get to win, shitbird. We do!
高楼区拆了
With these Towers down,
我们就得占领其余的平房区...
we need to take the rest of them low-rises...
还有Fayette街的那些街头
and all them Fayette Street corners.
占领? 怎么个占领法 Bodie先生?
Take them? Take them how, Mr. Bodie?
- 你说"去他的"然后把地盘占了 - 小子 没轮到你发言
- You say "fuck it" and take them. - Nigga, you ain't got the floor.
本席不允许你发言 怎么个占领法?
Chair don't recognize your ass. Take them how?
不知道
I don't know.
让那些在Fayette站街的黑鬼们 知道我们来真的 对吧
Just let them Fayette niggas know, you know, we serious, right?
你知道 谈不拢就动手
You know, get or get got.
是啊 像你去年在McCulloh街做的那样?
Yeah, like you did on McCulloh Street last year?
抢了地盘 全副武装...
Snatch the real estate, load up...
然后等着火拼 对吗
and just wait for some shit to happen, right?
不 伙计 我们已经操心够地盘了
No, man, we done worrying about territory, man...
占了哪个街角 哪栋公房
what corner we got, what project.
游戏的重点已经不是那个 而是产品
Game ain't about that no more. It's about product.
对
Yeah.
如果我们手上有最好的产品...
We got the best goddamn product...
无论在哪都能卖得掉 对吧?
so we gonna sell no matter where we are, right?
产品 混球们 产品
Product, motherfuckers. Product.
本席允许Slim Charles发言
Chair recognize Slim Charles.
主席 我们总得找个地方待着 不是吗
Chair, our people got to stand somewhere, don't they?
我是说 有再好的货又能咋样
I mean, all the product in the world don't mean nothing...
跑到其他傻帽的地盘上卖 还是会常常被揍...
if you constantly getting your ass whupped for standing on another fool's corner, man.
好吧
All right.
我们过去有六栋公楼 对吗
We had six of the Towers on the Terrace, right?
全天候营业
All running 24l7.
后来3栋给了Prop Joe的人...
But three of those we had to give to Prop Joe's people...
以换取更好的货源 对吧?
to upgrade the package that we was putting out there, right?
你们认为我们这笔买卖亏了多少?
Now, how much you think we lost in the deal?
好吧 答案是 我们赚得更多了
All right, the answer is, we made more.
地盘减半 货物加倍
Half the real estate, twice the product.
利润也增加了百分之八到九 嘿 想明白了
And our profit went up, like, eight or nine percent. Yo, get it straight.
货不好的话 有地盘也没用
Your territory ain't gonna mean shit if your product is weak.
去问问那些卖福特天霸的人...
Go ahead and ask them motherfuckers trying to sell them Ford Tempos...
你身边的人还整天在美国 开日产和德产车呢
and you got niggas riding around in Japanese and German cars in America all day.
地盘算个屁
Territory ain't shit.
尤其是考虑到抢地盘会...
Especially when you consider it's the fight for the territory...
带来死伤 而死伤会召来...
that be bringing the bodies and the bodies that bring the...
警察
police.
- 是啊 但我们怎么能站... - 嘿
- Yeah, but how we gonna stand... - Yo.
主席没允许你发言 伙计
Chair ain't recognize your ass, man.
- 我们怎么站在... - 站起来 伙计
- How we gonna stand on some... - Come on, man.
我们怎么能站在不属于我们的街角
How we gonna stand on some corner that's not ours?
我们有最好的货 对吧
Well, we got the best product, right?
可能的话 我们提供我们的货...
So the chances are, we gonna be able to bring in the competition...
作为他们的货源 加入竞争
by offering to re-up with us from our package.
懂了吗
Feel me?
大家一起赚钱 共享地盘
Everybody making money, sharing the real estate.
Slim Charles
Slim Charles.
但如果他们不从我们这进货呢?
But what if they don't cop our re-up, though?
等到那时候 我再操心吧
Well, I'm gonna worry about that when it happen.
在此之前 Charles先生 我们处事要像个生意人
Until then, Mr. Charles, we gonna handle this shit like businessmen.
买卖生财 先礼后兵
Sell the shit, make the profit, and later for that gangster bullshit.
说
Yeah.
主席有想到我们这样在外面 就像一群废物无赖?
Do the chair know we gonna look like some punk-ass bitches out there?
- 混球 冲你这话 我先废了你! - 嘿 嘿 String
- Motherfucker, I will punk your ass for saying such shit! - Yo, yo, String.
- 干嘛 - Poot有权发言
- What? - Poot did have the floor, man.
闭嘴 这黑鬼太无知了 不配发言
Shut the fuck up, man. This nigga too ignorant to have the fucking floor.
你们小子该学会用新的眼光看世界了
Y'all niggers need to start looking at the world in a new fucking light.
要学会像个成年人一样想事情
Start thinking about this shit like some grown fucking men.
而别只是个混迹街头的小混混 听见没有
Not some niggas off the fucking corner. You heard me?
休会
Adjourn your asses.
你们看上去糟透了
Y'all look like shit.
我们从黎明前就闷在那空屋里
Well, we been stuck in that vacant since before dawn.
- 能好到哪去 - 认识你是我的荣幸 警探
- How should we look? - Proud to know you, Detective.
你看上去不错
Nice look on you.
成功人士的打扮
Dress for success.
我一整天都监视着那混球Cheese送货
I watched that motherfucker Cheese take re-ups move weight all day,
他一步都没靠近过该死的电话
and not once did he go near a fucking telephone.
离他最近的一次是 打到他10尺外的小弟手上
Closest it comes is a call to a hanger-on's cell phone ten feet away.
这又回到了我和警督刚才讨论的话题
Which brings me back to what I was just discussing with the Lieutenant.
目前为止 我们已经 监听了这几部手机近6个月
So far, we've been up on some of these cell phones for nearly six months.
唯一能听到的有关毒品的谈话 都出自小角色之口
The only drug talk we have is from street-level small fry.
所以我们想两周之后...
So, the feeling is that maybe two weeks from now...
就不去向法庭申请延期了
we don't go back to the court for another extension.
就靠我们现有的证据起诉... 试着顺藤摸瓜 扳倒Cheese
We charge what we have... we try to roll someone up at Cheese
或其他Joe的其他小头目
or one of Joe's other lieutenants.
你开玩笑吧 我们现在 根本没有值得起诉的案子
What, are you kidding? We don't have a case worth making yet.
照这效率 永远不会有
And at this rate, we never will.
看在上帝的份上
For Christ's sake.
这方案理论上可行
As a plan on paper, it was a good one.
对港口案的调查 让我们得到了
We came out of the port investigation with good phone numbers...
Prop Joe手下的号码 以及监听这些号码的合理依据
for some of Prop Joe's people, and the PC to get up on those phones.
我保证如果我们的监听对象 能比街头混混再高一两个级别
I guarantee if we can push this thing a level or two above the street...
就能查到Prop Joe本人了
we're gonna start seeing Prop Joe himself.
查到Joe 就能查到Stringer
We start seeing Joe, we're gonna see Stringer.
我没法为结果未卜的监听 再争取更多的时间
I can't ask for more time on a wire that's going nowhere.
要么我们找到一个突破口 要么就放弃吧
Either we figure a way to punch through the wall or we let it go.
- Baker? - 是的 长官
- Baker? - Yes, sir.
那你一定是Castor
So you must be Castor.
是的长官 Aaron Castor警员
Yes, sir. Officer Aaron Castor.
你跟Lloyd Castor有亲戚关系?
You any kin to Lloyd Castor?
是的 长官 他是我叔叔
Yes, sir, that's my uncle.
好警察
Good police.
你知道自己在哪吗
Do you know where you are?
- 还有你 你们在哪 - 西区 警长
- You, too. Where are you? - The Western, Major.
此时此刻 你被人从后偷袭...
Right this very goddamn second, you getting your hind parts kicked...
你发出呼救
and you on the horn screaming for help.
而你的增援满世界乱找 因为他不知道你他妈在哪
And you got your backup looking all over the place 'cause he don't know where the fuck you are.
那就意味着我要向你的亲戚解释...
And that means I gotta explain to your next of kin...
你是怎么在我的监管下被人干掉的
how you went and got yourselves killed on my watch?
长官 我们在北山1034号 一楼后方
Sir, we're at 1034 North Mount, first floor rear.
很好
Good.
那北在哪边
Now, which way is north?
指出来
Point.
那是东
That's east.
你不认为在徒步追捕时
Now, don't you think if you're in a foot pursuit...
知道自己在朝哪个方向跑 会有利于你的后援吗
it might help your backup to know what direction you're running?
偶数能告诉你是北和西(门牌)
Even numbers tell you north and west.
奇数就是南和东
Odds, south and east.
指南针
Compasses.
学会分清方向前 先带在身上
Until you learn that much, you carry one.
欢迎来到西区
Welcome to the Western.
先生们 凶悍一点
Gentlemen, scuff yourself up a little.
要学会瞪人
And learn the stare.
嘿 Carv 你在哪
Hey, Carv, where you at?
我在北山1034号 一层点名室外的一张桌前
I'm at a desk outside the roll call room on the first floor of 1034 North Mount.
我的脚朝正西方 老二朝西南偏南
My feet are facing west and my dick is pointing south-southwest.
Bunny Colvin的这番话 从你们出生吸气起 就讲到现在了
Bunny Colvin's been giving that speech as long as you guys been sucking air.
知道自己在哪儿吗 傻鸟?
Where you at, shitbird?
你在我的地盘 戴着手铐 一副熊样 不是吗
You're in handcuffs, in my house, looking stupid, ain't you?
逃避追捕?
Fleeing and eluding?
有跟毒品有关的起诉吗
Do we have a drug charge here?
在规定的禁毒区闲荡
Loitering in a designated drug-free zone.
我换个说法 我们找到毒品了吗
Let me rephrase. Do we have drugs?
我们突击他所在街角时 他抓起这个包就跑
He raised up when we hit his corner and he grabbed this bag.
我们追捕并追回了包
We pursued and recovered the bag.
- 但没有毒品 - 他们还打了我
- But no drugs. - And they whupped my ass.
西区警风
Western District way.
我们得到了什么教训
So, what did we learn?
动用了我局里半数的警犬和直升机 去抓一个14岁的小鬼
Using half my district K-9 and the copter to bring a 14-year-old to bay.
我们得到了什么教训
What did we learn?
教训就是你没可能 从一分区贩毒角逃走..
That you can't raise up and run from a drug corner in Sector One...
妄想逃过我踹上你屁股的大脚
without my boot finding your ass.
对吧
Right?
抓稳了 抓稳了
I got it, I got it, I got it. Got it.
生铁 至少20美金
Cast iron. $20 at least.
是铜就更好了
It'd be better if it was copper. Be better if it was copper.
是啊 是金子更好
Yeah, be better if it was gold.
但你知道 生活就是得过且过
But you know, you gotta take life as it goes along, you know.
噢 该死 该死
Oh, shit, oh, shit.
- 你们搞什么 - 对不起
- What's wrong with you? - Sorry.
- 对不起也没用 - 靠 伙计 冷静 冷静
- We're past sorry. - Oh, fuck, man, chill. Chill, chill!
用不着使这个 伙计
We definitely don't need this, man.
现在知道错了吧
You think you fucked up now?
- 什么事 - 看看他们把我车搞得
- What's up? - Look what they did to my ride.
要么动手要么算了 我还要出门呢
Well, do it or don't. But I got someplace to be.
谢谢大发慈悲
Thank you for your kindness.
你们总得付出点代价 这有这的规矩
You all got to pay something, anything. There be a principle here.
我们要有钱就都给你了
If we had a dime, you'd have a dime.
我们现在有点拮据 好吗 我们正要去找收五金的
We're a little insufficient right now, okay? We're on our way to the metal man.
我们会回来 把该赔的都赔上 我保证
We'll come back and pay for everything. I promise you.
嘿 找完收破烂的 我们先去超市转转
Hey, hey, after the junk man, we gotta roll past K-Mart.
必须的
Definitely.
最后一个问题 局长
One last question, Commissioner.
回顾过去几个月
Looking back over the past couple months,
如果我没看错这些重案清单的话...
if I read the felony breakdowns correctly...
你们辖区内的枪击和恶性伤害事件直线上升...
you've been seeing an up-tick in shootings and serious assaults...
特别是在东区警局
in the Eastern District especially.
我们能认为你们已经在应对中吗?
Can we assume that you're already addressing this?
这个问题我让Bill来回答
Let me throw that over to Bill.
作为执行副局长
As Deputy for Operations,
他可以给出一个我们的回应
I'm sure he's got a handle on our response.
确实如此
I do indeed.
我来回答您的问题 议员...
In answer to your question, Councilman...
我向您保证我们已经增设了特警队...
I can assure you that we've put additional tactical teams...
在每个东区地段 从早7点执勤到下午3点
on a 7:00-to-3:00 shift in every Eastern sector.
此外 我们还安排机动队
Additionally, we've put the district flex squad...
早7点到下午3点值勤
on a 7:00-to-3:00 shift...
在这段恶性伤害事件频发的时段里
being as those are the hours... when we're seeing a spike in aggravated assaults.
谢谢 副局长
Thank you, Deputy.
还有问题问这两位可敬的警官吗
Anything else for these esteemed constables?
没了?
No?
那好 我们明晚的季度预算审查见
Okay, then, I guess I'll see you all tomorrow night for the quarterly budget review.
Erv 嘿...
Erv, hey...
你不介意的话 我想私下跟你聊聊
if you don't mind, I'd like to get with you about a couple things.
我们能一起吃午餐吗
Can we get lunch?
很荣幸 主席先生
Glad to, Mr. Chairman.
那么半小时后Werner餐厅见?
How about Werner's in a half-hour?
半小时后 好的
Half-hour, good.
- 你看见Watkins在后排吗? - 嗯
- You see Watkins in the back? - Yeah.
跟他在一起的女人是谁?
Who was that skirt with him?
他是穿橙色衣服的那个?
That's him there in the orange?
那就是Drac
That's Drac.
我们的救命稻草
Our last best hope.
监听线上最能扯的一个混球
Talkingest motherfucker I ever heard on a wiretap.
你听
Here, listen.
不 不 不 另一个 好的那个... 另一个 小子
No, no, no, the other thing. The good... The other thing, my nigga.
- 你说"他"? - 不 "她" 我说的是"她"
- You talking him? - No, her. I mean her!
可卡因 伙计 懂了吗  该死 你这蠢货...
Cocaine, nigga, you feel me now? Goddamn, you ignorant...
你上次监听到这个词是多久以前了?
When was the last time you heard that on a wire?
可惜他从不向重要人物汇报
Shame he doesn't report to anyone that matters.
现阶段Drac从Lavell Manns进货
Right now, Drac's re-ups are with Lavell Manns.
后者控制着Preston到Bond一带的街角
He's got those corners over on Preston and Bond.
他快同意出手给我们一包货
He was pretty close to selling us weight.
可以的 Sydnor已经磨了他好几个月了
No shit. Sydnor's been working toward him for a couple of months now.
Lavell是个战士 他不会倒戈Prop Joe的
Lavell's a soldier. He's not gonna roll up on Prop Joe.
那倒是 但如果我们诱捕到他...
That's true. But if we take him off with a hand-to-hand...
他们就会提拔别人来取代他
they gotta promote someone to replace him.
为什么是Drac?
Yaeah, why Drac?
这小子的特别之处?
One thing about our boy?
他是Prop Joe的外甥
That's Prop Joe's nephew.
甥舅之亲
On his mama's side.
22块
$20 and $2.
你们知道自己没穿裤子吧
Y'all know you ain't got pants?
Dominic就站在人群里
And there's Dominic standing in line.
当他终于接近了看着另一边的总统
And when he finally gets up to meet the President who's looking the other way,
他跑到卡特身后... 抓住他腰带一拽...
Dominic reaches around behind Carter.. grabs his belt, yanks it up...
特勤处肯定吓惨了
Secret Service must've shit.
他说"总统先生 记得我吗"
He says, "Hey, Mr. President, remember me?"
而卡特还真记得
And Carter actually remembers.
说"当然 Baltimore竞选活动上的 Dominic DiPietro"
Says, "Sure, Dominic DiPietro from Baltimore, on the campaign trail."
Dominic毫不停顿 用手指抵着吉米卡特脸...
And Dominic doesn't miss a beat. He puts his finger in Jimmy Carter's face...
说"那你三年前答应给我..."
and says, "So where's that money you promised me three years ago...
"翻修街道和巷子的钱呢"
"to fix up my streets and alleys?"
难以置信
Unbelievable.
这还不算 输给里根后 卡特回来演讲...
That's nothing. After losing to Reagan, Carter comes back here to speak...
Jefferson-Jackson日:纪念两位美国总统的节日
在一个Jefferson-Jackson日晚宴 还是什么场合... Dominic坐在他旁边
at a Jefferson-Jackson dinner or something... and Dominic is ushered up to him.
卡特问候他的健康 而Dominic说...
Carter asks about his health, and Dominic says...
"狗娘养的 我还等着你 给我翻修街道的钱呢"
"You son of a bitch, I'm still waiting on that money for my streets and alleys."
不是吧
Come on!
不骗你 卡特刚要打马虎眼
No shit. Carter's just grinning through those big teeth.
就有人抓了Dominic手臂 把他架了出去
Some guy grabs Dominic's arm, and off he goes.
那人说 "老天 Dominic..."
Guy says, "Christ, Dominic...
"你刚刚叫美国总统狗娘养的"
"you just called the President of the United States an SOB."
他耸耸肩说 "去他的 我不需要他 他已经输了"
He shrugs, he says, "Fuck him. I don't need him. He lost."
不 很有趣 很有趣
No, that's good. That is good.
这是我家乡流传的故事
And that is from whence I come.
第一选区令人骄傲的儿子
Proud son of the fighting First District.
但事实上...
But the truth is...
我不想成为另一个Dominic DiPietro式的庸人...
I don't wanna be just another muldoon like Dominic DiPietro...
议会中职位较低的成员坐在后面
甘做后座议员席
warming the backbench.
没法坐视不管现在城里发生的一切
Not with the way things are right now in the city.
我们每年损失1万到1万2千名居民
We're losing 10,000, 12,000 residents a year.
问他们为什么要搬到郊县去...
And when you ask them why they're moving to the county...
你知道他们怎么说吗
you know what they say?
- 学校 - 还有犯罪
- Schools. - And crime.
学校和犯罪
Schools and crime.
这就导致我们的税基刚过线...(税收不足)
And there goes our tax base right across the line...
而市长的反应 就像犯罪率飙升10%也很平常
and the Mayor's acting like a 10% bump in the murder rate is business as usual.
买单
Check, please.
知道吗
And you know what?
你聪明的话 市长亏待了你 你就来找我...
If you were smart, you'd come to me when the Mayor shorts you...
雇员也好 设备 加班费 车辆也罢
on hiring, on equipment, on overtime, on cars.
要是亏待了你 就来找我
You get the shit end of the stick, you come to me.
不公开 我知道你不能公开绕过市长
Not publicly. I know you can't cross the Mayor publicly.
但你可以私下找我...
But backdoor, you come to me...
我可以用附属委员会 来满足你的要求
and I can use that subcommittee to give you what you need.
谢谢
Thanks.
很好的提议
Kind offer.
Erv 我可以帮你
Erv, I can help you.
- 我们能改造这该死的城市... - 但很久以前
- And we can turn this damn city around... - But long ago,
我刚进警局时...
when I was just starting out in the Department...
我有幸了解到
I had the good fortune to be taught
什么叫指挥链
a little something about chain of command.
如今
And right now,
我身为代理局长...
in my capacity as Acting Commissioner...
要听命于Royce市长
I report to Mayor Royce.
咖啡我请 你愿意就留点小费吧
I got your coffee. Leave a tip if you want.
你为什么要见我
So what do you need to see me for?
- 你明天就要出狱了 对吧 - 对
- You're getting out tomorrow, right? - Yeah.
大概想叙叙旧吧
Probably trying to reach out.
- 你想先做什么 - 嗯?
- What you gonna do first? - Huh?
明天 你想干什么
Tomorrow. What you gonna do?
不知道
I don't know.
我知道先做什么 你不知道? 我知道
I know what be first. You don't know? I know what be first.
我想回家
I'm going home.
暂停
Time out!
继续
Back in!
注意空位 注意空位
Watch the hole. Watch the hole.
出狱男
Short-timer.
你知道自己只剩一天可待了吧
You know you got the one day left, huh?
过完今天就熬出头了
You done the one, just gotta do that other.
- 好吧 - 俗话说
- All right. - Like they say.
牢里的日子不过两天
You only do two day.
- 进来那天... - 和出去那天
There's the day you go in... The day you come out.
我不确定 我待了14年
I don't know. I did 14 years.
是啊 你是服了有点小长的刑期 没错
Well, yeah, you know. You did you a little stretch, true.
但你还是个战士 对吧
But you still a soldier, right?
你知道高楼都拆了吧
You know them Towers done came down now, huh?
大楼 Murphy公房 都成过去了 伙计
The Terrace? The Murphy Homes? All that shit gone, man.
你进来之后很多事都变了 你会发现的
A lot of things is different now since you been up in here. You'll see.
- 时过境迁 - 对 没错
- Lot of changes. - Yeah, no doubt.
但我的意思是 你知道 去他的
But, I mean, you know, shit.
有些事情不会改变 伙计 我是说 游戏还是游戏
Some things, they stay the same, man. I mean, the game's the game.
问题是 高楼倒了...
And the thing is, since the Towers is gone...
我就得转移阵地了 懂吗
I'm gonna need to take my thing up to some new places. You feel me?
你知道我很快就能回家了 对吧
You know I'm gonna be home soon enough, right?
首次假释听证会我就能出去 真的
Yeah, first parole hearing, I'm out. For real.
万事俱备
Shit is fixed right.
我回去后...
I come home...
靠
Shit!
有很对债要去讨 你懂我的意思吧
There's gonna be a little hell to be paid. You know what I mean?
一个好兵不愁缺活儿
A good soldier ain't gonna lack for work.
拿着这号码 伙计 出去后打给他
Take that number, man. When you out, you call.
我们会接洽你的 伙计 没问题
We'll hook you up, man, no problem.
你知道 就当是回家礼 好吗
You know, it's like a coming-home gift. All right?
记得打
Call it.
坐号子可能把他坐垮了
The joint might have broke him.
老大你说的可是个枪杀了 Elijah Davis的家伙
Boss, you talking about a homie walked up and shot Elijah Davis.
光天化日下在Pennsie和Gold街
Broad daylight, at Pennsie and Gold.
接着拿起电话拨了911...
Then picked up the phone, dialed 911...
对警察说 "我刚开枪打了一个黑鬼 来收尸吧"
told the police, "I just shot a nigga, come get him."
那哥们垮不了
That dude ain't breaking.
听着 你知道我们原来有20块 但我们得买两条新裤子
Look, we had the $20, you know. But we had to go buy some pants.
如果你收下差个数的钱...
So if you just take this short money...
我们明天一定回来给你 我们会把缺的钱的补上
we get back at you tomorrow, man. We get you on the comeback.
嘿 他想16块买两份
Yo, he want two for $16.
想法子弄两份 伙计 我想法子弄两份
Trying to get two, man. I'm trying to get two.
从这小混球身上弄
From this young motherfucker.
不行
No.
拜托 伙计 你看 我们现在手头紧...
Come on, man, see, you see, we a little short now...
但我明天一定再拿4块钱过来...
but tomorrow, I'll be right back here with the $4...
Joey说不行
Joey said no.
操蛋家伙
Fucking guy, man.
照这成本 我没法再负担电话监听了
At these prices, I can't afford more phone surveillance.
我理解
I'm aware of that.
现在的计划是诱捕一个小头目...
And right now, the plan is to go for a hand-to-hand on one lieutenant...
Proposition Joe手下的一个小弟
a couple rungs down from Proposition Joe.
然后策反他?
And then roll the lieutenant up?
我们认为往上牵扯的可能性不大
We don't think he'll have much roll to him.
Joe的人训练有素
Joe's people are pretty schooled.
我们希望他们会提拔一个中层的毒贩
The hope is that they promote this mid-level dealer,
一个叫Drac的傻帽来取代他
who's a fool to replace him. Name of Drac.
我们正在监听着他的电话
And we're on his cell phone.
如果他被提拔 可能会与 Joe或Joe的高层副手对话
If he gets promoted, maybe he talks to Joe or Joe's top people.
到那时 就可能查到Stringer Bell了
We get that far, maybe we start to see Stringer Bell.
你凭什么相信他们会提拔一个废材
What makes you think they'll promote the wrong man?
我们就经常这么干
We do it all the time.
听着 说到晋升 我如约 把对你的任命上呈市政厅了
Look, speaking of promotions, I sent yours over to the Hall, as promised.
结果呢
And?
在市长手里压着
And the Mayor's holding it up.
我认为他是想知道你妻子在搞什么
My understanding is he want to know what your wife is doing.
- 我妻子? - 对
- My wife? - Yeah.
有流言说她想竞选议会
There's a rumor that she's gonna take a run at a Council seat.
可能想把Eunetta Perkins拉下马
Maybe try to knock off Eunetta Perkins.
- 那是我妻子的事 - 是没错
- That's my wife's business. - Yes, it is.
但市长当Eunetta是盟友
But the Mayor counts Eunetta as an ally.
我们说好的是成立一个固定小队 给我下任警长的空缺
Our deal was for a permanent unit and the next vacancy for major.
队伍你有了
You got your unit.
我也把你的名字报给了市政厅
And I sent your name over to the Hall.
我遵守了诺言
I kept my word.
但市长...
But the Mayor...
在任命一个新指挥官前 想知道谁是他的朋友
he may wanna know who his friends are before he makes a new commander.
她说她会坐哪
Where'd she say she was gonna be at?
靠近球员休息处 一垒边上
Near the dugout, first-base side.
她会出现的 她什么时候 把他们带过来给你
She'll turn up. When is she supposed to bring them over to you?
第四局中
Middle of the fourth.
爸 我能吃个热狗吗
Dad, can I have a hot dog?
可以 卖热狗的过来就给你买
Yeah, as soon as the guy comes around.
说起来 卖啤酒的哪去了
Speaking of which, where's the beer man?
他们在那
There they are.
靠 他们位置真棒
Damn. They got great seats.
该死
Hell.
- 干嘛 - 她左边那是谁 那个西装男
- What? - Who's that on her left? The suit.
普通朋友?
Just a friend?
不 他们关系不一般
No, he's in the cake.
谁穿西装来看金莺队比赛 一半时间还耗在电话上?
Who comes to an Orioles game in a suit, spends half the time on a cell phone?
城里的律师
Downtown lawyer.
之类的有钱人
Something wealthy like that.
要是我们有更多就好了
Wish we had more of it.
搞个半针都不容易
Long way to go for half a shot.
明天会更好 Bubs
It'll be better tomorrow, Bubs.
什么样的瘾君子会关心明天
What kind of dope fiend be talking about tomorrow?
明天算个屁
Tomorrow ain't shit.
今朝有酒今朝醉 Johnny
Today, Johnny. Today.
我到处捡破铁 像狗一样拉去卖
I hunted down all that metal. Lugged it around like a dog.
还差点为一个刮痕送命 不得不哀声求饶
I nearly get killed over a scratch of metal, so that I gotta beg for my life.
裤子也没了 伙计 我该死的裤子
Lost my trousers, man, my fucking trousers.
接着又为半针死乞白赖的?
And then I'm begging again for half a shot?
我对天发誓 伙计 我都没爽到
I swear to God, man, I'm not even high.
- 我们刚错过了一个界外球 老爸 - 是吗
- We just missed a foul, Pa. - Yeah?
我们的座位太棒了 几乎要到场内了
Our seats are great. We're practically on the field.
对 我朋友 Dennis 他不时能弄到内部票
Yeah, my friend, Dennis, he gets company seats every now and then.
你坐哪
Where are you sitting?
中层看台 走吧
Mezzanine. Come on.
不 不 去吧 你们老爸一周没见你们了
No, no, you guys go. Your dad hasn't seen you all week.
别让他们把外套脱了 因为Sean感冒刚好 好吗
Now, don't take their jackets off, 'cause Sean's just getting over a cold. Okay?
Jimmy 是吧? Dennis Kerpelman
Jimmy, right? Dennis Kerpelman.
很好的孩子
Great kids.
总之 很高兴见到你
Anyway, nice meeting you.
你想买点什么吗
Do you want anything from the stand?
不 谢了
No, thank you.
别一直看到最后 明天还要返校
Don't stay till the last inning, 'cause it's a school night.
再见
Bye.
有两个不同朝向的喷溅痕迹 就在路缘外
You got spatter going in two different directions, just off the curb.
- 喂 - 西边有枪战
- Yeah. - Shooting on the west side.
又来一起? 老天 在哪
Another one? Christ, where?
北接和Pulaski街 轮到Cole了
North and Pulaski, Cole's up.
Cole在Belvedere设卡呢
Cole's working a cutting off Belvedere.
打给Crutchfield 看他能否从Westport的现场回来
Call Crutchfield. See if he's back from the Westport scene.
- Crutchfield? - 如果不行 就打给在家的Bunk
- Crutchfield? - If not, call Bunk at home.
- Bunk休息 - 去他的休息天
- Bunk's off day. - Well, fuck his off day.
我爱死这城市了
I love this town.
Perlozzo教练换投手的速度真快 不是吗
Perlozzo's pretty quick to yank a pitcher, ain't he?
我正琢磨着变成女人
I'm thinking of becoming a woman.
刚出炉的花生
Red-hot peanuts!
办公室的 喂
Office. Yeah.
我在看棒球
I'm at the ballgame.
棒球!
The ballgame.
对 那Cole呢 找他
Yeah, what about Cole? Call him.
靠
Oh, shit.
好吧
All right.
你相信吗 今晚一连五件案子
Can you believe this? They caught five tonight.
他们通知我休假日去上班
They're telling me I gotta come in on my day off.
- 五起? - 对
- Five? - yeah.
市风日下 伙计
City's jumping bad, man.
好吧 听着
Okay, listen.
- 我要去工作了 好吗 - 好吧
- I gotta go to work, all right? - All right.
Jimmy叔叔会...
Mr. Jimmy's gonna...
他会送你回家
He's gonna take you home.
乖乖的
(crowd booing)
都拜托你了 搭档
You're on your own, partner.
妈妈
Hey, Ma.
那么Erdman大道案呢
And Erdman Avenue?
没有弹道信息
No ballistic information.
你确定吗
Are you sure?
慢慢来 警长
Take your time, Major.
你相信吗 那个混账Carcetti...
Can you believe that cocksucker Carcetti?
觉得我会含血喷人
Thinking I'm gonna talk out of school.
随时候教 Marvin
Any day now, Marvin.
一个白人议员能给我什么 是一个黑人市长给不了的?
What can a white councilman give me that a black mayor can't?
当然没有 你做得对
No, you played it right.
在Erdman大道案中 有点38 口径的记录 长官
It was a .38 recorded on Erdman Avenue, sir.
那么你实际上是说 警长
So what you are, in effect, saying, Major,
比起把Monument街...
is rather than looking... at this
这一大堆的劫案并案处理...
cluster of robberies you had along Monument Street...
你选择分别派给不同警员独立调查
you chose to investigate each using separate personnel.
不 长官 其中三起是商店劫案...
No, sir, three of those cases were commercial robberies...
我们交给了市里的刑侦局
so we sent those downtown to CID.
我的人的责任是...
My people had responsibility...
该死 Marvin
God damn it, Marvin!
你刚刚用"责任"这个词...
Did you just invoke the word "responsibility"...
来解释为什么你搞不定这事?
to explain why you didn't get on top of this shit?
你刚刚这么说? 我不认为你明白这个词的意思
Did you just do that? I don't think you know what the word means.
尤其当我看着24小时报告 痛苦地发现...
When I look at the 24's and plainly see...
某个手持点38的混蛋 正在你的辖区横行霸道...
that some .38-caliber asshole is raping your entire district...
从Greenmount一直闹到Edison公路
all the way from Greenmount to fucking Edison Highway.
正是这种治安让我们...
It's policing like that that makes it possible for us to get hit...
一晚上遭遇五起该死的谋杀 各位
with five fucking homicides in a single fucking night, people!
可怜的Marvin
Poor fucking Marvin.
他死总比我们死好 对吧
Better him than us, right?
基于你的证词 交易本身就可以起诉...
Based on your testimony, the buy itself will be enough to charge...
不过能让他把话录在带子上就更好了
but you get him saying something on tape, it's even better.
你确定那家伙想批给你?
Are you sure this guy wants to be selling you weight?
我们可不想有强迫的感觉
'Cause we don't wanna be forcing this.
我磨了他两个月了 伙计
I been stroking this guy for two months, man.
他问的可不是这个
That's not what he asked you.
那家伙打定主意了 Kima
This guy is ripe and ready, Kima.
没问题的
It ain't no thing.
他们快准备就绪了
They're about ready.
你住在办公室 Cedric?
You living out of the office, Cedric?
好了 Drac就看你们的了
All right, Drac is depending on you people.
开工
Mount up.
安全回来
And find your way home.
感觉比一盎司轻了点 你不觉得吗
Look a little light to be an ounce, don't you think?
不 伙计 不可能轻 分量足够
No, man. Ain't nothing light, it's just settled, is all.
好吧 伙计 如果货真价实...
All right, man, if it does what it should...
我每周再回来找你买三四包
I'm gonna come back to you for three, maybe four a week.
没问题
Yeah, that could work.
那说好了?
We good, then?
说好了
We good.
- 可以了 - 逮捕他
- That's it. - Take him down.
- 有人告密 - 闭嘴
- Somebody snitching! - Shut the fuck up!
走吧 Lavell
Let's go, Lavell.
我是Cutty
It's Cutty.
有人说我可以打这个电话求助
Was told I could call for help.
Oxbow如何?
What about the Oxbow?
Fulton小区 Laurens街的Oxbow
The Oxbow on Laurens, at Fulton.
好吧
All right.
该死
Damn.
他们抓到Lavell带了一盎司
I'm saying, they caught Lavell with, like, a whole ounce.
这个量也许保释不了了
Might not be no bail for that much weight.
他们可能会告上联邦法庭 大张旗鼓
They might just take it federal, run wild on they ass.
你知道Joey会让别人 管Lavell的街角 对吧
And you know Joey gotta give Lavell's corner to someone, right?
- 可能轮到我了 - 这小子就是停不了嘴
- Might be my turn. - Our boy won't shut up.
Caroline 你说得好像这很糟一样
Caroline, you say that like it's a bad thing.
我们还是期待这被监听的 是会被提拔的候选人吧
Let's just hope we're listening to a candidate for elevation.
我听说过你 伙计
Oh, I heard about you, man.
你的名字以前很响亮
I hear your name used to ring out.
你是不是有东西给我?
You got something for me?
看到那矮子坐的地方了吗
You see where shorty's sitting at right there?
那里有些能帮你的
You'll find a little help.
等你准备好后 会有正事派给你 懂吗
But when you ready, we got some real work for you, all right?
老天
Jesus.
嘿 你好吗
Hey. How you doing?
挺好的
Okay.
- 我们刚好说到你 - 是吗
- We were just talking about you. - Really?
你认识妇联的Denise 当然还有Charles
You know Denise, from the sorority. Charles, of course.
- 很高兴见到你 警督 - 很高兴见到你
- Always a pleasure, Lieutenant. - Good to see you.
你大概没会过Delegate Watkins
And I don't think you've met Delegate Watkins.
- 你好吗 - 很高兴见到你
- How do you do? - Nice to meet you.
我们刚谈到你穿着警督的制服很帅气
We were saying you fill out a lieutenant's uniform nicely.
会给竞选海报增色不少
Makes an impression on the campaign lit.
那重要吗
That matters?
Marla是个新面孔 要较量的是个在位已久的对手
Well, Marla's a new face taking on a longtime incumbent.
- 恐怕任何细节都很重要 - 我会尽我所能帮上忙
- Everything matters, I'm afraid. - Well, anything I can do to help.
不打扰了 你们继续
I'll get out of the way and leave you all to it.
Marla 我得告诉你
Marla, I have to tell you
你和Cedric的合影用在传单上的效果很好
that your photo with Cedric works really well on the mailer.
我当然希望他了解将要面对的...
Yeah. I sure hope he knows what he's in for...
因为这对你们俩都是漫长的征途
because it's gonna be a long race for the both of you.
而且充满荆棘
And that is not going to go easy.
说起来 你们得准备些...
Speaking of which, you've got to make some...
老天 谁找来了媒体?
Jesus. Who called the media?
不 你以为他会尊重我 让我上位
No, you think the man might respect my shit enough to let me step up.
- 但事情却不是这样 - 为什么
- But it ain't even go like that. - Why not?
他要把Lavell的街角交给废材Cheese
He gonna give Lavell's corner to that off-brand nigger, Cheese.
你知道吗 Joe还是我叔叔呢
And you know what? Joe's my uncle and shit.
我是说 我是那个混蛋胖子的亲戚
I mean, I'm kin to the fat motherfucker.
那白痴要是做警察 现在该是副局长了
That idiot works for us, he'd be a deputy commissioner by now.
这案子真是背运
Ain't no luck at all to this case.
凭良心说 作为这个委员会主席...
And how, in all good conscience, can I,
我怎么能再批准更多额外的加班费预算...
as chairman of this subcommittee... authorize any more above-the-line overtime...
当面前的这堆数据清楚地告诉我...
when it's clear enough from the data in front of me...
这些钱不是花在一线警员 或办案警探身上...
that that money is not gonna go to line officers, or working detectives...
而是付给了司机和文书 甚至...
but is being used to pay for drivers and clerical and...
老天啊 看看这个 让两个警监...
And Jesus, look at this, so that two colonels...
和三个警长到佛罗里达的迈阿密 参加一个社区治安研讨会
and three majors can attend a community policing seminar in Miami, Florida.
主席先生...
Mr. Chairman...
这警局能从南部海滩学到什么...
What does South Beach have to teach this department...
让Baltimore长治久安的办法 局长?
about making Baltimore a safer place, Commissioner?
我不知道 你也不知道
I have no idea and you have no idea,
简直哭笑不得
and it is an embarrassment.
Cedric 他们走了
Cedric, they're gone.
我想感谢你
I wanna thank you for this.
没什么
No problem.
我知道这不容易
It's not easy, i know.
但他们大概认为我应该表现得...
But they seem to think it matters that I present myself as...
我没意见
I'm fine with it.
这么多年来你都在为我的仕途付出
All those years you were all about my career.
至少这也是我能为你做的 对吧
Well, it's the least I can do, right?
晚安
Good night.
我们没有压住来自他选区申请
We're not holding anything up in his district.
修路 派巡逻 安街灯...
Repaving, foot patrols, streetlights...
他的份都给了
He's getting his share.
除非这和他的选区无关
Unless it's not about his district...
是因为他本人
it's about him.
也许他盯上了什么
Maybe he's got big eyes for something.
盯上了什么
For what?
不会是我 不会是我的位置 不可能在这里发生(巴尔的摩黑人占多数)
Not me, not my chair, not in this town.
不 如果那家伙长得再白一点 就要透明了
Oh, no. If that guy came off any whiter, he'd be see-through.
不过真是那样 放马过来吧 事实上 老天爷帮帮他吧
But if that's it, come on with it. In fact, please, Jesus.
也许他想做施洗约翰
Or maybe John the Baptist.
削弱你 为别人做嫁衣
Soften you up for someone else.
- 若他想用犯罪率来整我们... - 用犯罪率来整我
- If he's gonna bang us on crime... - Bang me on crime.
你有没有什么办法跟这家伙谈谈?
Look, is there any way for you to talk to this guy?
- 让他别再来搞我? - 他是老一区的人
Keep him from crawling up my ass? He's old First District.
在那个选区我们没什么人脉
Not a lot of favors we can call in over that side of town.
我们总得向他展示点成绩 对吧
Well, we've got to show him something, right?
严重犯罪率降低四到五个百分点
Four to five percent drop in felonies.
还有谋杀
And murders.
把今年的谋杀案发率 控制在250起以下
Get the murders down to under 250 for the year.
恕我直言 市长大人 现在已经232起了
All due respect, Mr. Mayor, we're at 232 now.
你实际能控制在多少
What can you realistically do?
情况好的话 如果我们没日没夜地干...
Our best case scenario, if we bump overtime, is...
大概275起
275, maybe.
275起 老天
275, Christ.
这算是个承诺吧
That's a promise, right?
275...
那这个混账Carcetti就无话可说了
and this asshole Carcetti has no issue.
先生们 上头要求各区重罪犯案率...
Gentlemen, the word from on high is that felony rates district by district...
在年末之前降低五个百分点
will decline by five percent before the end of the year.
我们说的是一定要做到
We are dealing in certainties.
你们要把犯罪报告上的重罪犯罪率... 降低五个以上百分点 否则...
You will reduce the UCR felonies... by five percent or more, or...
我一直想这么说来着...
I've always wanted to say this...
别活着回来了
let no man come back alive.
另外 我们要把今年的 谋杀案控制在275起以下
In addition, we will hold this year's murders to 275 or less.
天啊
Christ.
有点难受 Foerster警监?
Feeling a little fazed, Colonel Foerster?
还是消化不良?
A little dyspeptic?
消什么? 不 长官 我很好
Dis-who? No, sir. I'm good to go.
告诉你们一件趣事
Here's a fun fact for you people.
如果Baltimore人口有纽约那么多...
If Baltimore had New York's population...
照这样的犯罪率 我们一年得出4000起谋杀案
we'd be clocking 4,000 murders a year at this rate.
我不接受任何借口
There is no excuse I will accept.
不管你们怎么做
I don't care how you do it.
但一定要做到
Just fucking do it.
副局长...
Deputy...
既然我们都对都市犯罪环境了然于胸...
as familiar as we all are with the urban crime environment...
我想我们都知道有些程序...
I think we all understand there are certain processes...
可以减少总的重罪数目
by which you can reduce the number of overall felonies.
你可以重新界定恶性伤害 或少算一件抢劫案
You can reclassify an agg assault... or you can unfound a robbery...
但你怎么能让一具尸体消失呢
but how do you make a body disappear?
这屋里没有谁的饭碗是铁打的
There isn't one of you in this room who isn't here by appointment.
如果你们还想继续戴着这袖章...
If you want to continue wearing those oak clusters...
就闭上嘴做正事
you will shut up and step up.
如果你们有谁 不能给我们想要的数字...
Any of you who can't bring in the numbers we need...
那就让办得到的人 来坐你们的位子
will be replaced by someone who can.
就这样
That is all.
老天 Bunny...
Jesus, Bunny...
你吃错药了?
what got into you?
我还有6个月就满30年 可以领警长养老金退休了
Another six months to my 30. I'm out the door on a major's pension.
他们能耐我何
The hell they could do to me.
蜘蛛包 红盖
Spider bags, red tops.
还有什么好点子?
Any other bright ideas?
- 窃听器怎么样 - 窃听器?
- How about a bug? - A bug?
对 窃听一两个混混聚集的街角
Yeah, bug one or two of the big corners where these mopes hang.
昨天打量了Ashland地段的街角
Watching those corners over on Ashland yesterday,
看到了垃圾桶 草丛 电线杆
I'm seeing dumpsters, weeds... maybe a utility pole.
你在正确的时间 正确的街角 按上一个 案子就成了
You hide a bug in the right corner at the right moment, you make this case.
我们没人 更别说钱了
We don't have the manpower. Not to mention the money.
再说有什么用? 我们离有价值的目标远着呢
And for what? We're still a long way from a quality target.
照我说 我们放弃监听 就现有证据起诉 查其他的去
I say we come down off the wire, charge what we can, and move on.
我们两年前就是草草收网 结果让一个大混蛋逍遥法外
We come down early two years ago and we left a real bastard on the street.
你是说还要让我被 同一个混蛋再打败一次?
You're telling me we're gonna let that same son of a bitch beat me again?
你有多少次放过像Stringer Bell这样的混蛋?
How many times do you let a cocksucker like Stringer Bell go around the board?
任他挣个盆满锅满
Collect another fucking $200 million.
桶里还有别的鱼 McNulty
There's other fish in the barrel, McNulty.
目标就是Stringer 没有更值得抓的了
Stringer's the target. There isn't a better fucker out there.
你也知道 警督
You know it, Lieutenant.
别让他在这事上蔫了
Don't you let him go soft on this.
就你整天对抗世界 是吧?
It's you against the world, is it?
我他妈又怎么了
What the fuck did I do?
红盖 蜘蛛包
Red tops, spider bags!
要吗
You up?
滚一边去 混球
Step the fuck off, motherfucker.
有需要就跟那些小鬼谈
You got a need, you talk to one of the young 'uns.
我不是来买货的 我来卖
I ain't in the market. I'm selling.
看样子应该是要跟你谈 老大
You look like the right person to be talking to, chief.
看来这块地头是你的
You seem like you steady running this shit here.
怎么 你是警察什么的?
What, are you some kind of police or something?
我跟警察八竿子打不着
I'm a long motherfucking way from the police.
我刚在Jessup监狱服完14年
I just finished a 14-year bit in Jessup.
拿到了点回家礼 G包
Got a package as a coming-home present. G-pack.
那你干嘛不自己卖
Well, why not sell that shit your own self?
我刚回家 不想又犯法
I just came home. I ain't trying to get my ass violated.
- 对半分 - 靠
- Even split. - Shit.
- 你是净赚 - 风险也是我担
- It's all profit to you. - Risk mine, too.
你以为我没在保释期什么的吗
What make you think I ain't on paper or some shit?
六四开
Sixty-forty.
行 把货给我小弟
Cool. Give your shit to my boy.
他很在行 明晚来拿钱
He good with it. Then come past tonight.
好
All right.
最后跟各位说一点
And one last item for you gents.
几天前直升机 在我们警局上空盘旋了一会儿
It seems that Foxtrot was hovering over the stationhouse a few days ago...
看到车库顶楼有十分壮观的 700到800个空啤酒罐
and caught a lovely view of about 700 or 800 discarded beer cans on the garage roof.
说真的 下班后不允许在警局停车场喝酒
Seriously, no off-duty drinking on the station lot.
如果你真又拿着个啤酒罐...
And if you do find yourself holding a beer can...
别朝屋顶扔 带回家去
don't throw it on the roof, take it home with you.
拜托 伙计们 这备忘录 可来自我们挚爱的副局长
Come on, guys, the memo came down from our beloved Deputy of Operations.
好了 散会
All right, get out of here.
别被逮到
Don't get captured.
稍息
At ease.
日班有什么情况
Anything from day shift?
没什么要写报告的
Nothing that'll make the papers.
那好 副警长来之前我要巡查辖区
All right, then, I'm gonna ride the district until the Deputy Major gets in.
要找我无线电联系
If you need me, hit the radio.
分销?
Distribution?
持有
Possession.
还有游荡
And some loitering.
游荡?
Loitering?
还有在警官面前摆出一副屌样 老大
And behaving like assholes in the presence of sworn officers, boss.
Barksdale案
警察来了
Five-o creeping.
午夜换班了
It's midnight relief coming in.
这些什么玩意
What the hell is all this?
前事不忘 后事之师
You don't look at what you did before, you do the same shit all over.
我要回去了
I'm out of here.
姓名:Barksdale D'Angelo
2002年9月19日进入Jessup监狱服刑
红盖蜘蛛包 混搭货
Spiders with a red top! One and one!
他在哪
Where he at?
蜘蛛包 来买蜘蛛包
Spider bags! Got those spider bags!
你他妈看什么
The fuck you looking at?
干嘛 你也想试试?
W-hat, do you want a go?
我的分成呢?
Just my split.
不走运
Some bad luck there.
警察来了 端了一两个藏毒点
The police came through, snatched up a ground stash or two.
正好是你的货 悲剧 是吧
Shit happened to be yours. Fuck, right?
- 你有编号吗 - 编号?
- You got a number? - A number?
在过去 玩家要说自己的货被警察缴了...
Back in the day, when a player tried to say he lost a package to the police...
他就得给个编号上报(案件编号)
he had to give up a number for the report.
现在不是过去了
Well, we ain't back in the day.
我懒得跟你解释了
I'm getting fucking tired of your ass.
对 滚远点 混球
Yeah, walk it off, motherfucker.
过气的老杂种
Fucking old-school-ass bitch.
有蜘蛛包 买二送一
Got them spider bags. Two'll get you three.
- 什么 - 要吗
- What? - You up?
蜘蛛包 买二送一
Spider bags, two gets three.
要不要
You up or you not?
- 你搞什么 小子? - 噢 伙计 菜鸟一个
- What you doing, boy? - Oh, man! Dumb rookie.
你认不出警察吗
Don't you know five-o?